Inventory of the Philip Whitwell Wilson writings
Hoover Institution Archives
Philip Whitwell Wilson writings
1907-1937
XX277
Wilson, Philip Whitwell, 1875-
11 manuscript boxes (4.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Newspaper and periodical articles, relating primarily to British politics. Includes daily columns by P. W. Wilson in the London Daily News, 1907-1917, and weekly columns in The Truth, 1912-1937, relating to activities of the British Parliament.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material requires at least two weeks advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
British journalist; member of parliament, 1906-1910.
Scope and Content of Collection
Newspaper and periodical articles, relating primarily to British politics. Includes daily columns by P. W. Wilson in the London Daily News, 1907-1917, and weekly columns in The Truth, 1912-1937, relating to activities of the British Parliament.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Great Britain. Parliament.; Journalism Great Britain.; World War, 1914-1918--Great Britain.; Great Britain Politics and government 1901-1936.; Journalists.
- Daily columns by P. W. Wilson in the London Daily News, 1907-1917 (Box 1-7)
  - The Daily News, Feb-April 1907 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - The Daily News, April-June 1907 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - The Daily News, June-Aug 1908 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - The Daily News, May-Nov 1908 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - The Daily News, 1908 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
  - The Daily News, Jan- March 1909 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - The Daily News, March-June 1909 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - The Daily News, June-Aug 1909 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - The Daily News, Aug -Oct 1909 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - The Daily News, Oct-Dec 1909 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - The Daily News, Jan-April 1910 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - The Daily News, April-June 1910 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - The Daily News, June-Sept 1910 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - The Daily News, Sept-Dec 1910 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - The Daily News, 1911 (Box-folder 4: 3-5)
  - The Daily News, July-Oct 1911 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - The Daily News, Oct-Dec 1911 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - The Daily News, July-Oct 1912 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - The Daily News, Oct-Dec 1912 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - The Daily News, Jan-April 1913 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - The Daily News, June-Aug 1913 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - The Daily News, July-Dec 1913 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - The Daily News, Jan-May 1914 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - The Daily News, May-Aug 1914 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - The Daily News, Jan-July 1915 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - The Daily News, Sept-Dec 1915 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - The Daily News, Jan-March 1916 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - The Daily News, April-June 1916 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - The Daily News, July-Sept 1916 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - The Daily News, Oct-Dec 1916 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - The Daily News, 1917 (Box-folder 7: 6)
- Weekly columns by P.W. Wilson in The Truth, 1912-1937 (Box 7-9)
  - Truth, April-Dec 1912 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Truth, Jan-Nov 1913 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Truth, 1914 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Truth, 1915-1925 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Truth, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Truth, 1913-1923 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Truth, 1925-1930 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Truth, 1931-1937 (Box-folder 9: 3)
- Miscellaneous, circa 1900-1920 (Box 9-10)
  - Miscellaneous news clippings, documents, and booklets, circa 1900-1920 (Box-folder 9: 4-6)
  - Miscellaneous clippings from newspapers including The Guardian, M.A.P., and Signal, 1908-1912 (Box-folder 10: 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous news clippings including P.W. Wilson's columns in the London Daily News, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 10: 6-7)